You've seen the logistic regression model,
you've seen the loss function that
measures how well you're doing
on the single training example.
You've also seen the cost function that
measures how well your parameters W and
B are doing on your entire training set.
Now let's talk about how you can use
the gradient descent algorithm to train or
to learn the parameters
W on your training set.
To recap here is the familiar
logistic regression algorithm and
we have on the second
line the cost function J,
which is a function of
your parameters W and B.
And that's defined as the average
is one over m times has some of
this loss function.
And so the loss function measures
how well your algorithms outputs.
Y hat I on each of the training examples
stacks up compares to the boundary
lables Y I on each of
the training examples. The
full formula is expanded out on the right.
So the cost function measures
how well your parameters w and
b are doing on the training set.
So in order to learn a set
of parameters w and b,
it seems natural that we
want to find w and b.
That make the cost function J of w,
b as small as possible.
So, here's an illustration
of gradient descent.
In this diagram, the horizontal axes
represent your space of parameters w and
b in practice w can be much higher
dimensional, but for the purposes of
plotting, let's illustrate w as a singular number and b as a singular number.
The cost function J of w,
b is then some surface above
these horizontal axes w and b.
So the height of the surface represents
the value of J, b at a certain point.
And what we want to do really is
to find the value of w and
b that corresponds to the minimum
of the cost function J.
It turns out that this particular
cost function J is a convex function.
So it's just a single big bowl,
so this is a convex function and
this is as opposed to
functions that look like this,
which are non convex and
has lots of different local optimal.
So the fact that our cost function J of w,
b as defined here is convex,
is one of the huge reasons why we use
this particular cost function J for
logistic regression.
So to find a good value for
the parameters,
what we'll do is initialize w and
b to some initial value may be
denoted by that little red dot.
And for logistic regression,
almost any initialization method works.
Usually you Initialize the values of 0.
Random initialization also works,
but people don't usually do that for
logistic regression.
But because this function is convex,
no matter where you initialize,
you should get to the same point or
roughly the same point.
And what gradient descent does is
it starts at that initial point and
then takes a step in
the steepest downhill direction.
So after one step of gradient descent,
you might end up there because it's
trying to take a step downhill in
the direction of steepest descent or
as quickly down who as possible.
So that's one iteration
of gradient descent.
And after iterations of gradient descent,
you might stop there, three iterations and
so on.
I guess this is not hidden by the back of
the plot until eventually, hopefully you
converge to this global optimum or get to
something close to the global optimum.
So this picture illustrates
the gradient descent algorithm.
Let's write a little bit more of the
details for the purpose of illustration,
let's say that there's some function
J of w that you want to minimize and
maybe that function looks like
this to make this easier to draw.
I'm going to ignore b for
now just to make this one dimensional plot
instead of a higher dimensional plot.
So gradient descent does this.
We're going to repeatedly carry
out the following update.
We'll take the value of w and update it.
Going to use colon equals
to represent updating w.
So set w to w minus alpha times and
this is a derivative d of J w d w.
And we repeatedly do that
until the algorithm converges.
So a couple of points in the notation
alpha here is the learning rate and
controls how big a step we take on
each iteration are gradient descent,
we'll talk later about some ways for
choosing the learning rate,
alpha and second this quantity here,
this is a derivative.
This is basically the update of the change
you want to make to the parameters w,
when we start to write code to
implement gradient descent,
we're going to use the convention
that the variable name in our code,
d w will be used to represent
this derivative term.
So when you write code,
you write something like w equals or
cold equals w minus alpha time's d w.
So we use d w to be the variable name
to represent this derivative term.
Now, let's just make sure that this
gradient descent update makes sense.
Let's say that w was over here.
So you're at this point on
the cost function J of w.
Remember that the definition
of a derivative is the slope
of a function at the point.
So the slope of the function is really,
the height divided by the width
right of the lower triangle.
Here, in this tension to
J of w at that point.
And so here the derivative is positive.
W gets updated as w minus a learning
rate times the derivative,
the derivative is positive.
And so you end up subtracting from w.
So you end up taking a step to the left
and so gradient descent with,
make your algorithm slowly
decrease the parameter.
If you had started off with
this large value of w.
As another example, if w was over here,
then at this point the slope here or
dJ detail, you will be negative.
And so they driven to send update with
subtract alpha times a negative number.
And so end up slowly increasing w.
So you end up you're making w bigger and
bigger with successive
generations of gradient descent.
So that hopefully whether you
initialize on the left, wonder right,
create into central move you
towards this global minimum here.
If you're not familiar with
derivatives of calculus and
what this term d J of w d w means.
Don't worry too much about it.
We'll talk some more about
derivatives in the next video.
If you have a deep knowledge of calculus,
you might be able to have a deeper
intuitions about how neural networks work.
But even if you're not that familiar
with calculus in the next few videos
will give you enough intuitions
about derivatives and
about calculus that you'll be able
to effectively use neural networks.
But the overall intuition for
now is that this term represents
the slope of the function and we want to
know the slope of the function at
the current setting of the parameters so
that we can take these steps of
steepest descent so that we know what
direction to step in in order to go
downhill on the cost function J.
So we wrote our gradient descent for
J of w.
If only w was your parameter
in logistic regression.
Your cost function is
a function above w and b.
In that case the inner
loop of gradient descent,
that is this thing here the thing you
have to repeat becomes as follows.
You end up updating w as
w minus the learning rate
times the derivative of
J of wb respect to w and
you update b as b minus
the learning rate times
the derivative of the cost
function respect to b.
So these two equations at the bottom of
the actual update you implement as in
the side, I just want to mention one
notation, all convention and calculus.
That is a bit confusing to some people.
I don't think it's super important
that you understand calculus but
in case you see this, I want to make sure
that you don't think too much of this.
Which is that in calculus this term
here we actually write as follows,
that funny squiggle symbol.
So this symbol,
this is actually just the lower
case d in a fancy font,
in a stylized font.
But when you see this expression,
all this means is this is the of J of w,
b or
really the slope of the function J of w,
b how much that function
slopes in the w direction.
And the rule of the notation and calculus,
which I think is in total logical.
But the rule in the notation for
calculus, which I think just makes things
much more complicated than you need to
be is that if J is a function of two or
more variables,
then instead of using lower case d.
You use this funny symbol.
This is called a partial derivative
symbol, but don't worry about this.
And if J is a function of only one
variable, then you use lower case d.
So the only difference between whether you
use this funny partial derivative symbol
or lower case d.
As we did on top is whether J is
a function of two or more variables.
In which case use this symbol,
the partial derivative symbol or
J is only a function of one variable.
Then you use lower case d.
This is one of those funny
rules of notation and
calculus that I think just make things
more complicated than they need to be.
But if you see this
partial derivative symbol,
all it means is you're measuring
the slope of the function with
respect to one of the variables,
and similarly to adhere to the,
formally correct mathematical notation
calculus because here J has two inputs.
Not just one.
This thing on the bottom should be written
with this partial derivative simple,
but it really means the same thing as,
almost the same thing as lowercase d.
Finally, when you implement this in code,
we're going to use the convention
that this quantity really the amount
I wish you update w will denote
as the variable d w in your code.
And this quantity, right,
the amount by which you want
to update b with the note by
the variable db in your code.
All right.
So
that's how you can
implement gradient descent.
Now if you haven't seen calculus for a few
years, I know that that might seem like
a lot more derivatives and calculus than
you might be comfortable with so far.
But if you're feeling that way,
don't worry about it.
In the next video will give you
better intuition about derivatives.
And even without the deep mathematical
understanding of calculus,
with just an intuitive
you will be able to make your
networks work effectively so
that let's go into the next video, we'll
talk a little bit more about derivatives.